## BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

CLOUD PLATFORM ENGINEER – DELIVION MÜLHEIM

ONLINE

http://bharathkumarraju.com
in in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraju

CONTACT

Chennai, Tamil Nadu t: +49 15143155538

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com

**BIO DETAILS** 

DOB: 12-June-1987 Passport: J7879295

Solutions Architect - Associate

Certified

amazon



## **SUMMARY:**

Over 7 years IT experience in DevOps and CLOUD in mission critical environments across the Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, **automation**, **continuous deployment(CICD)** pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

Able to communicate effectively at all levels and able to work on own initiative or within a larger group including during crisis situations.

**TECHNICAL PROFILE:** 

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Puppet, Git, Bamboo, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx, Liquibase.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat, packetbeat.

Monitoring/Log Sysdig, Newrelic, Datadog, App Dynamics, Sumologic, sensu, flapjack, Grafana, graphite.

Programming Python, Shell Scripts, Java.

RDBMS Oracle, MS SQL, Sybase, PostgreSQL, MySQL.
OS Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu.

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform.

Certifications AWS Solution Architect and VMware Cloud Professional

**EXPERIENCE:** 

Delivion GmBH,

Germany (Marh 2018-Present) Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs. Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications.

Worked in k8s setup and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps.

Worked on SonarQube automation and upgrade using ansible.

StandardChartered,

Chennai (Oct 2016-Present) Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline. Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic Stack. Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution. Introduced Nginx as Gateway & Dockerized it with F5 as load Balancer.

Worked on Micro-service Architecture with spring config server for dynamic variable substitution in ansible.

**Trimble Navigation,** 

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform.

Chennai

Created Development, QA, Stage, Production stacks & maintaining them securely using robust VPC design.

(Jun2014-Sep2016) Worked on REST API Development using AWS Gateway and AWS Lambda (Python). Automated resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort.

Implemented application monitoring using DataDog & integrated with AWS environment.

Hewlett-Packard,

Chennai (Mar2011-May2014) Performing Software installation, upgrade/patches, troubleshooting & maintenance on UNIX Servers. Administrated DHCP,DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Automating the deployment of Middleware Applications to RHEL DEV/PROD servers on VMWare ESX.

**EDUCATION:** 

MCA-Post Graduation Information System and Computer Science

(Jun2007-Jun2010) UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

**BSC- Graduation** Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

(Jul2004-May2007) Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics.

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

**INTERESTS:** 

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.